RAHAM NESSLER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- graham@grahamnessler.com 😵 http://www.grahamnessler.com/ 📞 (215) 804-7381 (USA)
- ♥ gness1804 in https://www.linkedin.com/in/gness1804 gness1804

SUMMARY

I am a former history professor and <u>published author</u> turned software developer with experience in front-end frameworks such as React, Angular, and React Native as well as back-end technologies such as Postgres, SQL, and Node. I am an extremely fast learner, and in my day to day work, I consistently apply not only my technical training from the Turing School of Software and Design but also the analytical thinking and teaching skills gained from my former profession. I believe that the core purpose of technology is to improve people's lives, and I look forward to joining a company that will allow me to grow and further this mission.

SKILLS

CORE TECHNICAL TOOLBOX: React.js, Redux, React Native, JavaScript/ES6, Ember, Angular, ExpressJS, jQuery, JSON, CSS/SASS, HTML5 Canvas, TDD, Websockets, HTML5, Firebase, Git/Github, Postgres and SQL, Webpack, Vim, Enzyme and Selenium, Mocha and Chai, Swift

ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES: Sketch, Atom, Sublime Text, Microsoft Office, Blackboard, Turnitin

OTHER SKILLS: Agile, Web accessibility/ARIA, Excellent writing skills, Proficient in Spanish, French, and English, Working knowledge of Brazilian Portuguese, Mentoring and leadership, Teaching and public speaking, Teamwork and group collaboration

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Webdriver IO · Add some clarifications to guide.md

Debugpolitics.com Add hover color change for footer links and a readme

Spell check for Atom text editor Revised readme for clarification

Promise It Won't Hurt (Nodeschool course) Some small changes for clarity (to instructions)

PROJECTS

FareHarbor Toolkit

This is a powerful tool creator for FareHarbor, an online travel services company, created with colleague Ryan Westlake, It consists of three tools--a search input tool, a footer tool, and a bottom modal tool--and a config setup that allows FareHarbor to easily customize these three and other tools for their clients' websites. The project was built to help increase conversions for FareHarbor's clients.

My core contributions: created the search input tool and footer tool; wrote documentation on these tools; co-created the config setup; co-authored intro section of documentation; created tests for my two tools.

JavaScript, ExpressJS, Selenium Webdriver, Sketch.

"Flash Shopper"

This is an independent solo project undertaken outside of the Turing School curriculum. It consists of a grocery list where users can enter in an item name, aisle, quantity, and a note. Users can also choose a category (such as "Bread") from a dropdown menu, which will then populate the aisle number (currently only for my local King Sooper's). The user can also sort items alphabetically and by aisle number, edit items, and delete items. I recently also added a "pantry" feature with common recurring items that can be added to the list with a single click.

React, Redux, Firebase, JavaScript, SASS/CSS, Webpack. See also my version in React Native

(For other projects, please see my portfolio).

EXPERIENCE

Florida Atlantic University Visiting Professor of History · Aug 2015 to May 2016, Aug 2015 to May 2016 · Boca Raton, FL

Taught courses in United States, Caribbean, Latin American, and global history to around 200 students

Bentley University
Post-Doctoral Fellow - Sep 2013 to Jul 2015 - Waltham, MA

- Completed book manuscript
- Taught an undergraduate course on dictatorships in modern Latin America

Texas A&M University--Commerce

Ad Interim Assistant Professor of History · Aug 2012 to May 2013, Aug 2012 to May 2013 · Commerce, TX

· Taught courses in United States and Latin American history at both the graduate and undergraduate levels

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software and Design

Certificate in Front End Engineering 2017

University of Michigan PhD History 2011

College of William and Mary

BA History 2005